[
    {
        "question_text": "Which of the following is the best know semi-conductor?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Carbon",
            "Selenium",
            "Gallium arsenide",
            "Germanium"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Germanium"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "The process of adding semiconductor <b>called</b>?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Transmutation",
            "Doping",
            "Polarization",
            "Hydrolysis"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Doping"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "In the D.C electric motor, which of the following does not apply?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Spindle",
            "Fixed carbon brushes",
            "Powerful magnetic field",
            "Slip rings"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Slip rings"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "In the A.C. generator, which of the following does not apply?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Fixed carbon brushes",
            "Spindle",
            "Split rings",
            "Powerful magnetic field"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Split rings"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "Which of the following law is an application of the law of conservation of energy?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Maxwell's law",
            "Lenz's law",
            "Faraday's law",
            "Fleming's left hand rule"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Faraday's law"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "The induction coil is a device for generating a?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "High voltage from low A.C. source",
            "Low voltage from high D.C. source",
            "High voltage from a low D.C. source",
            "Low voltage from a low A.C. source"
        ],
        "correct_option": "High voltage from a low D.C. source"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "Which of the following pairs of quantities have equivalent units?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Work done and moments",
            "Energy and momentum",
            "Strain and Young's modulus",
            "Energy and pressure"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Work done and moments"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "The dimension of power is?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "ML-1 T2",
            "ML2 T-2",
            "ML2 T-3",
            "ML-1 T-2 -2"
        ],
        "correct_option": "ML-1 T2"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "A body starts from rest and moves with an acceleration of 8ms for 10 seconds. Find the distance during the 8th second?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "256m",
            "196m",
            "120m",
            "60m"
        ],
        "correct_option": "60m"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "One of the limitations of Bohr's model of the atom is that it does not explain?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "The stability of the atom",
            "Variation of the atomic radius",
            "The line spectra of hydrogen",
            "The experiment determination of the atomic radius"
        ],
        "correct_option": "The line spectra of hydrogen"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "X-rays were discovered by?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Isaac Newton",
            "Michael Faraday",
            "Sir J.J. Thompson",
            "W. Roentgen"
        ],
        "correct_option": "W. Roentgen"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "Natural radioactivity was discovered by?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Niel Bohr",
            "Henri Becquerel",
            "De Broglie",
            "Rutherford"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Henri Becquerel"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "The number of atoms of a radioactive substance is initially8 x 1016. If the number reduces to 2 x 1016 in 64 minutes. What is the half-life of the substance?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "82min",
            "16min",
            "8min",
            "4min"
        ],
        "correct_option": "82min"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "During the electrolysis of copper (II) sulphate solution, an ammeter showed a steady current reading of 1.0A for 2hr and 6.6 x 104 kg of copper were liberated. Calculate the % error in ammeter reading?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "12%",
            "11%",
            "1.2%",
            "1.1%"
        ],
        "correct_option": "11%"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "An electric lamp has the following markings 230V. 250W, how long would it take the kilowatt-hour when lamp to use one connected to a 230V mains?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "8.0hr",
            "6.0hr",
            "4.0hr",
            "2.0hr"
        ],
        "correct_option": "4.0hr"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "Which of the following statements is correct about a temperature semi-conductor at room?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "The valence band is filled and the conduction band is partly filled",
            "The valence band is completely filled and the conduction band is completely empty",
            "The valence band is almost filled and the conduction band is almost empty",
            "The valence band is empty and the conduction band is filled"
        ],
        "correct_option": "The valence band is almost filled and the conduction band is almost empty"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "Which of the following statements is not correct?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "When ebonite rod is rubbed with wool the ebonite rod acquires a negative charge and wool acquires a positive charge",
            "When a glass rod is rubbed with silk the glass rod acquires a positive charge while silk acquires a negative charge",
            "When fur is rubbed with ebonite rod the ebonite rod acquires a positive charge and fur a negative charge",
            "When wool rubbed with an ebonite rod is brought near silk rubbed with a glass rod attraction occurs."
        ],
        "correct_option": "When fur is rubbed with ebonite rod the ebonite rod acquires a positive charge and fur a negative charge"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "With the Daniel cell the depolarizer is?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Tetra-oxo-sulphate (IV) acid",
            "Ammonium chloride solution",
            "Copper sulphate solution",
            "Manganese (IV) Oxide"
        ],
        "correct_option": "Copper sulphate solution"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "Which of the following arrangements gives the electromagnetic radiation in their ascending order of wavelength?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "Radio waves/ ultraviolet rays. x-rays. y- rays",
            "y -rays. x-rays. ultraviolent rays. radio waves",
            "x-rays. y -rays. radio waves. ultraviolent Rays",
            "Ultraviolent rays. y -rays. x-rays. radio waves"
        ],
        "correct_option": "y -rays. x-rays. ultraviolent rays. radio waves"
    },
    {
        "question_text": "Which of the following statements is not correct about the astronomical telescope under normal adjustment?",
        "optional_text": "Answer the following questions",
        "school_code": "etc",
        "school": "UNIBEN",
        "year": "2005",
        "subject": "Geography",
        "options": [
            "The final image is at infinity",
            "The principal foci of the objective and eye piece coincide",
            "The final image is at principal focus of the eye piece",
            "The distance between the lenses is equal to the sum of their focal lengths"
        ],
        "correct_option": "The final image is at principal focus of the eye piece"
    }
]